aacn.org 2019-05-05

# Privacy Policy - AACN

AACN respects and values the privacy of visitors to our website. We collect data about our visitors in order to conduct transactions, improve our users’ experiences, and keep our community informed.

We want you to know that we follow best practices for keeping your information safe.

This privacy policy describes how we use your information to improve your experience and how we seek to protect and secure your private information when you use our website.

If you would like to opt out of AACN data collection, you can contact us directly via email ([info@aacn.org](mailto:info@aacn.org?subject=Opt%20Out%20From%20Privacy%20Policy)), telephone at 949-362-2000, or mail at:

American Association of Critical Care Nurses  
101 Columbia   
Aliso Viejo, CA   
92656

### What Information Do We Collect?

**Information You Provide** – We collect information you provide, such as email addresses, telephone numbers, and payment information. Some of this information may be personally identifiable information, which means that it can be tied to a specific individual. 

This information allows us to communicate with individuals in our community and to conduct online transactions.

**Behavioral Data** – We collect information about a specific user’s online browsing behaviors, such as what you search for, which pages you visit, what products and services you purchase, what links you click, and what articles you download, etc.

This data allows us to deliver more relevant offers and personalized content to each visitor based on inferences about their interests. We, our service providers and third party online companies such as ad networks and advertising partners may automatically collect certain technical information from your computer or mobile device over time and across different websites when you use our website. See the sections below discussing cookies and similar technologies for a description of these tools and how they are used.

**Other Automatically Collected Information** – We also collect other information that allows us to track the use of our web pages at an aggregate and de-identified level, to improve our overall web experience. We may use and share this de-identified data for any purpose at our discretion. 

### How Do We Collect Your Information?

**User Provided Data**

We ask you directly to provide your information when you register on our site, subscribe to a newsletter, respond to a survey, fill out a form, provide us with feedback on our products or services, attend an event, or enter information on our site.

**Analytics Tracking Code**

We use web analytics code to track information about your implicit web use patterns and online behaviors each time you visit our website, to better understand your needs and interests.

**Cookies**

We use small snippets of code to track your visits including both cookies and web beacons.

Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site's or service provider's systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information.

We use cookies to:

  * Help remember and process the items in the shopping cart.
  * Understand and save user's preferences for future visits.
  * Keep track of advertisements.
  * Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third-party services that track this information on our behalf.

If you do not wish to be tracked, you can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to decline all cookies. You can do this through your browser settings. Since each browser is a little different, look at your browser's Help Menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookie settings.

If you turn cookies off, some features that make your site experience more efficient may not function properly.

**Web beacons**

Web beacons, which are also known as clear GIFs, Web bugs or pixel tags, are often used in combination with cookies. They are images (often transparent) that are part of Web pages. At AACN, Web beacons allow us to count users who have visited certain pages and to generate statistics about how our site is used. _They are not used to access personally identifiable information._

Unlike cookies, you cannot decline Web beacons. However, setting your browser to decline cookies or to prompt you for a response will keep Web beacons from tracking your activity.

**Do Not Track**  
We honor Do Not Track signals and do not track, plant advertising or analytics cookies, or use behavioral advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place. For more information, see All About Do Not Track.

### How Do We Use Your Information?

We may use the information we collect from you for a number of purposes, including, but not limited to:

  * To personalize your experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested.
  * To improve our website in order to better serve you.
  * To allow us to better serve you in responding to your customer service requests.
  * To administer a promotion, contest, survey or other site feature.
  * To quickly process your transactions.
  * To send periodic emails regarding your order or other products and services.
  * To follow up with you after correspondence (live chat, email or phone inquiries).
  * To send you periodic mailings with information on new products, services or upcoming events.

**

### How Do We Protect Your Information?

**

AACN has taken reasonable security measures at our physical facilities to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you.

### When Do We Share Data?

We may disclose data we collect from you for the following purposes, or as required by law.

**For Advertising Purposes**

We use cookies and web beacons as described above to collect and share information with our advertising partners to enable targeted advertising.   These programs allow us and advertisers to advertise and provide offers to you on other sites you might visit that align with interests inferred by your behavior on our site.  For example, if you have been looking at NTI sessions, we might send you an offer for early registration as a sponsored post in your Facebook feed. Connecting website visitors with these kinds of personalized offers is known as **Online Behavioral Advertising**.

You can opt-out of the use of your information by certain third parties who use it for targeted advertising by going to [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices)

**For Third Party Offers**

The AACN Mailing List* is provided periodically to other carefully screened organizations who wish to send information regarding various research projects, educational courses, professional recruiting, clinical publications, or other products and services that are identified as aligned with our mission and would be of interest to acute and critical care practitioners.

List rentals are also made available to NTI Exhibitors.

Where provided, you can use the check box option in online registration forms to avoid inclusion in this list.

**Local AACN Chapters**

The AACN Mailing List* is shared with your local AACN Chapter for their use in recruiting and promoting chapter activities.

You can opt-out of list sharing for all purposes by calling 949.362.2000, by emailing ([info@aacn.org](mailto:info@aacn.org?subject=Opt%20Out%20From%20Privacy%20Policy)), or by sending mail to the above address.

_*The mailing list includes only names and mailing addresses. Your email address and phone number are never shared._

**Data Requests from the Concerned Party**

Upon request, we provide site visitors with reasonable access to certain of their own information, including their unique identifier (e.g. customer number or password), transaction information (e.g. dates and amounts of past purchases), contact information (e.g. name, address, and phone number), or a description of the information that we maintain about them.

You can change or correct your personal information:

  * By accessing your MyAACN Account Page
  * By sending email ([](mailto:mailto:info@aacn.org?subject=Opt%20Out%20from%20Privacy%20Policy)[](mailto:info@aacn.org?subject=Opt%20Out%20From%20Privacy%20Policy)[info@aacn.org](mailto:info@aacn.org?subject=Opt%20Out%20From%20Privacy%20Policy))
  * By calling us at 949-362-2000
  * By sending a request by mail to the above address

**

### Privacy Law Compliance

**

We take your privacy very seriously and we act in accordance with established laws as well as best practices to secure your personal information.

**Your California Privacy Rights**

If you reside in California and have provided your personally identifiable information to us, you may request information once per calendar year about our disclosures of certain categories of your personally identifiable information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. Such requests must be submitted to us via email ([](mailto:info@aacn.org)[info@aacn.org](mailto:info@aacn.org?subject=Opt%20Out%20From%20Privacy%20Policy)), telephone at 949-362-2000 or by mail at the above address.

**Children's Privacy**

We do not specifically market to children under the age of 13 years old or knowingly collect personal information from minor children under the age of 13.

**Email Opt Out**

If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails from AACN, you can email ([info@aacn.org](mailto:info@aacn.org?subject=Opt%20Out%20From%20Privacy%20Policy)), call us at 949-362-2000 or send mail to the above address and we will promptly remove you from ALL correspondence.

### Changes to Privacy Policy

From time to time, we may use customer information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice. If our information practices change, we will post the policy changes on our website to notify you of these changes and provide you the opportunity to opt out of these new uses. AACN encourages you to check back regularly for any changes to our Privacy Policy.

Visitors may prevent their information from being used for purposes other than those for which it was originally collected by sending email ([info@aacn.org](mailto:info@aacn.org?subject=Opt%20Out%20From%20Privacy%20Policy)), calling 949-362-2000, or writing to us at the above address.

### Contact Us

If you feel that this site is not following its stated privacy policy, please contact us directly via email ([info@aacn.org](mailto:info@aacn.org?subject=Opt%20Out%20From%20Privacy%20Policy)), telephone at 949-362-2000 or by mail at:

American Association of Critical Care Nurses  
101 Columbia   
Aliso Viejo, CA   
92656

_Last Updated 10/04/16_
